Let's do another thing, adding the user to remote desktop user group.
If you see in Windows, we have multiple groups, so you can see administrator, backup operator,
cryptographic operators, and remote desktop users and remote management users.
We've protect us needs to perform any kind of lateral movement, they will be checking.
So, whether the user has a privilege, has added into the remote desktop user group or not.
Whether the user or the RDP user or not, remote desktop user or not.
So, we can, in a previous section, going through the "Bluthand & Shock" and "The Undestooled,"
so who are the users having the remote desktop administrators, who is in the "What" group.
So, the threat actors will be also enumerating few informations, whether the account was enabled,
account was already added in the remote desktop users.
If the account was not added, the threat actors will be tried to add the account
to the remote desktop user group.
So, the command was really simple, you need to add, you need to give a local group
and you need to select which group you need to add.
So, in our scenario, the group was remote desktop user and the user name was "unusers/act."
So, let's execute this command.
So, now the command completed surface will be checked, whether the user has enabled,
has added into the administrator group.
So, here you can see the user was an administrator and the user was added into the remote desktop user
as well as the user was added into the remote management users.
So, this is how you need to figure out something going on in the RDP.
So, while you are performing any threat analysis or investigation of foreign six instead of
the machine, so if you see in this three commands, collide either the RDP or modifying
the firewalls or rules or adding some users in the RDP group.
So, that will be considered a bit suspicious because they are in the post exploitation
thing and they will be using, they will be going to use RDP for a lateral movement.
So, I hope you have clear understanding about why we executed these three commands.
We can see RDP in the next section, how the threat attacks will be used RDP for remote
access and lateral movement also a celestial command and control.
So, the RDP will be if you check in miter, so here you can see remote service and remote
desktop protocol.
So, in command and control also you can you can see the RDP, RDP will be there as
well as in lateral movement, you can see RDP will be there.
So, it is exploiting a remote service and remote service, here you can find the RDP as
well as we can use a command and control RDP protocol for command and control, remote
desktop software, remote access hardware or something and this is really a useful thing
to do lateral movement, ok. So, let us hop off from here, we will continue our discussion
in our next section, see you guys, bye bye.